It's official. Elon Musk has cancelled
monetization at X. And I personally
think this is a fantastic set of news. A
lot of this probably comes from the
experiment that Nikita revealed back on
June 30th. If you weren't watching,
don't worry, I'll catch you up, but it's
official. The monetization program at X
is dead in the way we know it. I'm going
to explain how it's changed. Here's the
email that came in. We are going to look
at that email. We're going to break down
what's different. But first, you need a
little bit of backstory. You got to go
all the way scroll all the way back on
your ex timeline to June 30th. And then
you're going to see why one of these big
changes came into place. So on June
30th, Nikita, who literally just stepped
down from X and and uh their role at X
right before the SpaceX lockup, which a
lot of people speculated was because
they wanted to sell shares that they may
have had. We don't even know if they had
shares. we we it doesn't matter, right?
But there was a lot of speculation as to
why they stepped down. People really
like this person, you know, I thought
they were useful. It seemed like every
single day they tried to improve the
platform. But this was very interesting.
In a 3% experiment, they removed the top
30 highest paid revenue share accounts
from the 4U timeline.
And when they did that, they actually
saw that both time spent and daily
active usage went up. So, basically,
think about it like this. If you're on X
and there's a piece of breaking news,
okay, like somebody like me who pays for
a wire service, let's say I pay for a
wire service, I see a piece of breaking
news, I see, okay, Goldman Sachs uh
reports a 7.2% passive stake in Nebius
Group as of June 30th. Oh, that's pretty
cool. All right, let's say then I take
that breaking news and I throw it into X
and I'm one of the first people to post
it or I post it algorithmically, which I
can. I I don't I actually provide this
for free right now. I I don't I don't
Yeah, you could go get this for free in
the Meet Kevin app. You just download
the Meet Kevin app in the uh Google or
Apple uh app store. You could even get
the desktop version afterwards if you
want. But anyway, the point is you could
use this wire service for free and you
could get this information minute by
minute. This is what the news companies
use, right? And you don't actually have
to use X to get that minute-byminute
news. This is why I like this. But what
happens on X is usually, in my opinion,
you get because of the monetization
system, you get a lot of people who are
going to share the same thing over and
over and over again, and then they just
quote tweet it and X basically has to
pay monetization for the same piece of
news over and over and over again. And
people aren't actually contributing new
value. They're just flooding your feed
with the same news story and not really
anything new. And I think what X is
doing here is they're basically saying,
"Look, we want stuff that's unique." In
fact, when you look at the email, you
could see them say here, "Breaking news,
expert insights, unique experiences,
creativity, and commentary that moves
culture forward." In my opinion, this is
basically just look, you could sum all
this crap up, which sounds, you know,
you a little window dressed in terms of
how they would it. I think you could
literally just say, "Hey, listen. If you
actually provide value, we will gladly
pay you." [laughter]
But if you're just quoting the same crap
over and over again, we ain't going to
pay you. Let me give you another
example. So, I posted a comment on the
semi analysis article like a couple
hours ago when they first posted it.
They still haven't responded to me
because I think there's a fatal flaw in
their article. And at the same time,
while I think there's a fatal flaw, and
I left a comment on it, asking about it
because I actually read the article,
you've got a lot of people like this
guy, and a lot of people are doing this,
they literally just quote tweet semi
analysis. They screen grab one picture
from the story, and then they go and say
something like WTF or this is insane or
rocket emoji. Now, think about it. You
have the semi-analysis people who took
the effort to write a long freaking
article. I disagree with the substance
of the article. I haven't quote tweeted
or said anything, right? But anyway,
semi-analysis post their article. Now
you got three people who are
collectively probably getting 10 times
as many impressions as the original
writers. And so X is now paying 10 times
as much money to all these knuckleheads
who are just going WT, [screaming]
[laughter]
right? X is paying 10 times as much
money to all these knuckleheads and the
people who actually wrote the story are
like whatever maybe people will sign up
for our you know wire our substack or
whatever it is they sell right so fine
now I personally think if somebody now
quote tweets this and says hey there's a
fatal flaw in your article why did you
assume this which directly contradicts
your assumption over here that's kind of
a fatal flaw why don't you address it
that is a way to provide more value in
my opinion because rather than just
going oh my gosh look at this article
you're going hey there's actually some
more nuance here there's a problem here
or this is good because of this this is
good because of that or bad because of
this whatever right that's providing
more value I think that's what they're
trying to do and I think they're trying
to do that with Grock probably they'll
use some kind of AI to figure that out
speaking of Grock it's worth noting that
AI infrastructure revenue obviously was
the focus of uh SpaceX's last earnings
but if you actually look closely ly at
page 44 of the earnings filing, you
could see that Grok and X subscriptions
increased to 258 million. But while
Grock and X subscriptions, so like X
premium, where you get monetized or see
fewer ads, well, that went up to 258
million, they actually lost on ads. They
had ad growth fall. We went from 426
down to 367. A $59 million decline in ad
rates.
That's not good. So, whatever growth
we're seeing from subscribers is getting
offset by a decline in advertising. So
advertising down, yeah, less money to
make up for that from premium users, but
if usage and uh uh time like how many
days in a row you're going on the
website is going down, we're causing
problems. We need to fix this. And it,
in my opinion, does go back to creating
people to share slop on the platform.
And I am actually very supportive of
this platform, this this change. I think
this is a really good idea. I think you
should only get paid if you provide more
perspective or value. Like if somebody's
talking about a stock, you know, pull up
the actual financials and add to the
conversation. But anyway, the revenue
sharing program will be retired
effective September 7th. You'll get your
final pay on September 11th. Beginning
September 8th, you'll be able to apply
for original content creators rewards
program. To join, you'll have to meet
certain eligibility like ID
verification, blah blah blah. Uh and
then this is over here what qualifies.
So this is interesting. Qualified
impressions are unique impressions from
premium users.
Oh. Oh, interesting. So, so you can only
now get paid by impressions that come
from premium users. Okay. On the home
timeline feed where at least 50% of the
post is visible, right? Cuz if you're
scrolling and you know you only see a
fraction of the post, that that might
not necessarily count. Oh, look at that.
I actually replied, [laughter]
"Dude, I didn't know I was going to find
my own reply comment on this." July 1st.
So, I replied to Daily Lady. Yeah,
because they copy and paste the same
[laughter]
I mean uh nailed it. [laughter]
But, but anyway, impressions from the I
mean, my ex usage has plummeted. I mean,
partly my ex usage has plummeted because
I use a wire service. I honestly I think
everybody should just use a wire
service. uh it's it's much faster. You
don't get distracted. You could kind of
keep this up uh like on another screen
or whatever. And then you you see when
the headlines come through. I mean, I
know people who use the Meet Kevin app
and and they're not getting charged for
it. But anyway, impressions for the same
account counted more than one per post.
That's fine. Like Yeah. Like is if the
same person keeps going back like I've
gone back to that semi-piece like five
times, right? Paid, promoted, or
artificially generated or fraudulent
impressions would not monetize. I mean,
that's fair. Okay. So, what's considered
original content? Well, here is what's
not considered original. Copied content.
Copied text, images, or videos copied
from other people. Minimally modified.
Uh, aggregating content, primarily
combining news from other people with no
new perspective. Yeah. A substantial new
perspective. Content taken from other
platforms and reposted by someone other
than the original creator. Yeah. Yeah.
And so, you'll have some new
requirements now. You'll have to be a
premium or premium plus or business
subscriber. You need to have at least
500,000 home timeline impressions from
verified users in the last 90 days. Oh,
have at least 500 verified followers.
Actively post original content. Wow. So,
I mean, a lot of people are are going to
lose a revenue stream here. And and
you'll have to be continuously
uh eligible like meet these
requirements. So, so it sort of be this
this ongoing test basically on on a
rolling basis. It looks like it looks
like they're doing a rolling 90-day um
uh test. And then of course, they've got
a list of countries where there's
eligibility. That's interesting. And
they're also limiting payouts to $30.
That makes sense. I mean, you get like
$2 distribution or whatever. Like, who
cares? The accounting work for that just
just isn't worth it. This is actually
really, I think, a smart thing for X.
Again, my X usage has been declining,
but that's me personally. Maybe yours is
up as much, but like I noticed when they
monetized X, the value that I got from X
actually declined a lot. So, I haven't
posted there much. I I I did recently
post a really nice piece there. Uh, but
it was actually like [music]
just totally original, like not anything
anybody else had any input into. It was
just about Kevin and Margin Dad is what
it was about. I still got to make a
video on that. Uh, but this is a good
thing. So, I think hats off to SpaceX. I
actually think it will help them sell
more advertising space because the
content will be better. So, good for
them. Uh, I think this is actually a W
for Elon Musk and SpaceX.
>> Why not advertise these things that you
told us here? I feel like nobody else
knows about this.
>> We'll we'll try a little advertising and
see how it goes.
>> Congratulations, man. You have done so
much. People love you. People look up to
you.
>> Kevin Pra there, financial [music]
analyst and YouTuber. Meet Kevin. Always
great to get your take.